<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<root>
    <doclet-version-NOT-library-version>1.00</doclet-version-NOT-library-version>
    <class>
        <name>anywheresoftware.b4a.agraham.threading.Threading</name>
        <shortname>Thread</shortname>
        <comment>This is the Thread object that actually runs a Basic4Android Sub on a separate thread.
Normally Threads should be created as Process objects so they will persist as long as 
the application exists. This will make their behaviour easier to predict and control
rather them being Activity objects which will need recreating when an activity resumes
which might leave orphan threads running that could cause unexpected problems.</comment>
        <objectwrapper>java.lang.Thread</objectwrapper>
        <owner>process</owner>
        <event>Ended(endedOK As Boolean, error As String) 'The thread has terminated. If endedOK is False error holds the reason for failure</event>
        <method>
            <name>Yield</name>
            <comment>Note that this method affects the caller and not this Thread object.
This causes the calling thread to sleep for zero milliseconds which has the
effect of suspending the thread and immediately rescheduling it for execution.</comment>
            <returntype>void</returntype>
        </method>
        <method>
            <name>RunOnGuiThread</name>
            <comment>Causes the specified Sub to be scheduled for execution on the main GUI thread.
This mechanism is the only way a thread can access GUI items. This call returns
immediately. If it is necessary for the thread to wait for the result of the
GUI operation then it should wait on a Lock that will be reset by the called Sub
after it haas completed the GUI operation. Sometimes it seems that if the user
presses the back button, and maybe in other scenarions, then Android loses the
message and the GUI thread doesn't get it and the Sub isn't run and the Lock
isn't freed so it may be advisable in this case to use WaitFor with a reasonably
long timeout and retry until it returns True.</comment>
            <returntype>boolean</returntype>
            <parameter>
                <name>sub</name>
                <type>java.lang.String</type>
            </parameter>
            <parameter>
                <name>params</name>
                <type>java.lang.Object[]</type>
            </parameter>
        </method>
        <method>
            <name>Initialise</name>
            <comment>Initialises the thread object with the given event name.</comment>
            <returntype>void</returntype>
            <parameter>
                <name>processBA</name>
                <type>anywheresoftware.b4a.BA</type>
            </parameter>
            <parameter>
                <name>eventname</name>
                <type>java.lang.String</type>
            </parameter>
        </method>
        <method>
            <name>Start</name>
            <comment>Starts the new thread of execution. The specified Sub will be called by the newly
started thread and passed the provided parameters. Returns True if the thread was
started, False if the thread is already running and a new one could not be started.
Threads are always started as daemon threads which are threads that will be killed
when the main application thread terminates. Because Exceptions in a separate thread
are not passed back to the main thread and can cause the application to hang any
uncaught Exceptions thrown in the thread Sub are trapped and saved in the threads
Error property. The Thread ends when the thread Sub returns or throws an uncaught Exception.
When the thread terminates, for whatever reason, the Ended event is raised. If the thread
terminated normally then the Ended event endedOK parameter is True otherwise endedOK is
False and the error parameter contains the reason which is the same string returned by
reading the Error property. If a Sub includes a Try - Catch it can always rethrow the
exception using an ExceptionEx object.</comment>
            <returntype>boolean</returntype>
            <parameter>
                <name>sub</name>
                <type>java.lang.String</type>
            </parameter>
            <parameter>
                <name>args</name>
                <type>java.lang.Object[]</type>
            </parameter>
        </method>
        <method>
            <name>Sleep</name>
            <comment>Note that this method affects the caller and not this Thread object.
Causes the thread to sleep for the specified number of milliseconds suspending
the thread before rescheduling it for execution. The precision of the length of
sleep is not guaranteed, the Thread may sleep for more or less time than requested</comment>
            <returntype>void</returntype>
            <parameter>
                <name>mSecs</name>
                <type>int</type>
            </parameter>
        </method>
        <method>
            <name>Join</name>
            <comment>Blocks the calling thread until the called thread finishes its execution
and dies or the specified timeout expires, whichever happens first.
Passing a value of zero or less blocks the calling thread until the called
thread finishes its execution and dies.</comment>
            <returntype>boolean</returntype>
            <parameter>
                <name>mSecs</name>
                <type>int</type>
            </parameter>
        </method>
        <method>
            <name>Interrupt</name>
            <comment>Posts an interrupt request to this thread. The thread is only interrupted
if the thread is doing I/O or is in a wait-state (having called wait() on
a LockFlag. If the thread is blocked in a join() or sleep() it will be
woken up, its interrupt status will be cleared, and it will receive an
InterruptedException. If the thread is blocked in an I/O operation of an
InterruptibleChannel it will have its interrupt status set and receive a
ClosedByInterruptException and the channel will be closed.
If the thread Sub code is running freely without waiting or blocking and
it knows that it might be expected to stop on an Interrupt then it should
periodically check the IsInterrupted property and exit gracefully if it is True.
Otherwise the recommended way of stopping a thread is for it to inspect
a global variable whose value will tell it to stop or perform some other action.</comment>
            <returntype>void</returntype>
        </method>
        <method>
            <name>IsInitialized</name>
            <comment></comment>
            <returntype>boolean</returntype>
        </method>
        <property>
            <name>NormalPriority</name>
            <returntype>int</returntype>
            <comment>The normal (default) priority value assigned to threads.</comment>
        </property>
        <property>
            <name>Exception</name>
            <returntype>java.lang.Exception</returntype>
            <parameter>
                <name>e</name>
                <type>java.lang.Exception</type>
            </parameter>
            <comment>Because Exceptions in a separate thread are not passed back to the main thread
and can cause the application to hang any Exceptions are trapped in the Thread
object Start method and the Exception object saved in the Exception property
and the thread Ended event raised on the main GUI thread. Reading this property
returns  the saved Exception object.</comment>
        </property>
        <property>
            <name>IsInterrupted</name>
            <returntype>boolean</returntype>
            <comment>Returns a boolean indicating whether the thread has a pending interrupt request
(True) or not (False). It also has the side-effect of clearing the flag.</comment>
        </property>
        <property>
            <name>Running</name>
            <returntype>boolean</returntype>
            <comment>Returns True if the thread has already been started and still runs code
(hasn't died yet). Returns False either if the thread hasn't been started yet
or if it has already started and run to completion and died.</comment>
        </property>
        <property>
            <name>MaxPriority</name>
            <returntype>int</returntype>
            <comment>The maximum priority value allowed for this thread.</comment>
        </property>
        <property>
            <name>MinPriority</name>
            <returntype>int</returntype>
            <comment>The minimum priority value allowed for a thread.</comment>
        </property>
        <property>
            <name>Version</name>
            <returntype>double</returntype>
            <comment>Returns the version number of the library.</comment>
        </property>
        <property>
            <name>Error</name>
            <returntype>java.lang.String</returntype>
            <parameter>
                <name>error</name>
                <type>java.lang.String</type>
            </parameter>
            <comment>Because Exceptions in a separate thread are not passed back to the main thread
and can cause the application to hang any Exceptions are trapped in the Thread
object Start method and the Exception message saved in the Error property and
the thread Ended event raised on the main GUI thread. Reading this property
gets the description of any exception caused by the thread code and is the same
string that is passed to the Ended event.</comment>
        </property>
        <property>
            <name>Priority</name>
            <returntype>int</returntype>
            <parameter>
                <name>priority</name>
                <type>int</type>
            </parameter>
            <comment>Sets or returns the priority of the Thread.</comment>
        </property>
    </class>
    <class>
        <name>anywheresoftware.b4a.agraham.threading.Threading.ExceptionWrapper</name>
        <shortname>ExceptionEx</shortname>
        <comment>This is the Exception object that provides facilites for handling exceptions.
As Basic4Android has a more basic Exception object this one is called ExceptionEx
to avoid a name conflict.</comment>
        <objectwrapper>java.lang.Exception</objectwrapper>
        <owner>process</owner>
        <method>
            <name>Initialize</name>
            <comment>Constructs a new ExceptionEx with the current stack trace and
the specified message.</comment>
            <returntype>void</returntype>
            <parameter>
                <name>message</name>
                <type>java.lang.String</type>
            </parameter>
        </method>
        <method>
            <name>StackTraceElementMethod</name>
            <comment>Returns the name of the method belonging to this StackTraceElement.</comment>
            <returntype>java.lang.String</returntype>
            <parameter>
                <name>index</name>
                <type>int</type>
            </parameter>
        </method>
        <method>
            <name>ToString</name>
            <comment>Returns a string containing both the name of this Exception and the
message, if any, provided when it was created.</comment>
            <returntype>java.lang.String</returntype>
        </method>
        <method>
            <name>StackTraceElementLine</name>
            <comment>Returns the line number in the Java source for the method belonging
to this StackTraceElement. Only useful for the gurus amongst us!</comment>
            <returntype>int</returntype>
            <parameter>
                <name>index</name>
                <type>int</type>
            </parameter>
        </method>
        <method>
            <name>StackTraceElementFile</name>
            <comment>Returns the name of the Java source file containing the method belonging
to this StackTraceElement.</comment>
            <returntype>java.lang.String</returntype>
            <parameter>
                <name>index</name>
                <type>int</type>
            </parameter>
        </method>
        <method>
            <name>IsInitialized</name>
            <comment></comment>
            <returntype>boolean</returntype>
        </method>
        <method>
            <name>Throw</name>
            <comment>Throws this Exception.</comment>
            <returntype>java.lang.String</returntype>
        </method>
        <method>
            <name>StackTraceElement</name>
            <comment>Returns a string describing the stack trace element at position
index in the stack trace for this Exception. Index 0 is the one
at the top of the stack and identifies the method and line number
in the Java source code at which this Exception was thrown.</comment>
            <returntype>java.lang.String</returntype>
            <parameter>
                <name>index</name>
                <type>int</type>
            </parameter>
        </method>
        <property>
            <name>Name</name>
            <returntype>java.lang.String</returntype>
            <comment>Returns the name of the class of this Exception which identifies
the type of the Exception.</comment>
        </property>
        <property>
            <name>Message</name>
            <returntype>java.lang.String</returntype>
            <comment>Returns the information message which was provided when this
Exception was created. Returns null if no message was provided at
creation time.</comment>
        </property>
        <property>
            <name>Version</name>
            <returntype>double</returntype>
            <comment>Returns the version number of the library.</comment>
        </property>
        <property>
            <name>StackTraceLength</name>
            <returntype>int</returntype>
            <comment>Returns the number of stack trace entries in the stack trace for
this Exception.</comment>
        </property>
        <property>
            <name>Cause</name>
            <returntype>java.lang.Exception</returntype>
            <comment>Returns the cause of this Exception, or Null if there is no cause.</comment>
        </property>
        <property>
            <name>StackTrace</name>
            <returntype>java.lang.String</returntype>
            <comment>Returns a string containing the entire stack trace for this Exception.</comment>
        </property>
    </class>
    <class>
        <name>anywheresoftware.b4a.agraham.threading.Threading.SemaphoreWrapper</name>
        <shortname>Lock</shortname>
        <comment>This is the Lock  object that is a thin wrapper over an Android Semaphore object.</comment>
        <objectwrapper>java.util.concurrent.Semaphore</objectwrapper>
        <owner>process</owner>
        <method>
            <name>WaitFor</name>
            <comment>Causes the calling thread to wait on this lock until it becomes free or until
the timeout expires. If the specified waiting time elapses without the lock
becoming free then the value False is returned. If the time is less than or equal
to zero, the method will not wait at all. If this is locked then the calling thread
will halt until another thread frees it or the timeout expires. If during the wait
the lock is freed then the waiting thread  will proceed and and this method returns
True and the lock is immediately set again. If it is already unlocked then the
thread does not wait but proceeds immediately returning True and setting the lock
as it does so.</comment>
            <returntype>boolean</returntype>
            <parameter>
                <name>timeout</name>
                <type>int</type>
            </parameter>
        </method>
        <method>
            <name>Initialize</name>
            <comment>Makes a new locked Semaphore, with zero permits, or an unlocked Semaphore
with one permit. A Semaphore initialised unlocked can be used to control
access to a resource. To acquire a resource the sequence for a thread is
Wait() - use resource - UnLock(). A Semaphore initialised locked can be
used to flag events across threads. The sequence is for the waiting thread
to call Wait() and the invoking thread to call Unlock().</comment>
            <returntype>void</returntype>
            <parameter>
                <name>locked</name>
                <type>boolean</type>
            </parameter>
        </method>
        <method>
            <name>Wait</name>
            <comment>Causes the calling thread to wait on this lock until it becomes free.
If this is locked then the calling thread will halt until another thread
frees it, the waiting thread will then proceed and the lock is imediately
set again. If it is already unlocked then the thread does not wait but
proceeds immediately setting the lock as it does so.</comment>
            <returntype>void</returntype>
        </method>
        <method>
            <name>Unlock</name>
            <comment>Frees the lock allowing one other thread waiting on it to proceed.
If no threads are waiting then the next thread that tries to wait
will proceed immediately setting the lock as it does.</comment>
            <returntype>void</returntype>
        </method>
        <method>
            <name>Lock</name>
            <comment>Sets the lock on this Semaphore. Any thread now trying to wait on it
will halt waiting for some other thread to unlock it.</comment>
            <returntype>void</returntype>
        </method>
        <method>
            <name>IsInitialized</name>
            <comment></comment>
            <returntype>boolean</returntype>
        </method>
        <property>
            <name>LockState</name>
            <returntype>boolean</returntype>
            <comment>Returns the state of this Lock, True if locked, False otherwise.
Note that in some situations this might become invalid as soon
as it is read if another thread uses this Lock.</comment>
        </property>
        <property>
            <name>Version</name>
            <returntype>double</returntype>
            <comment>Returns the version number of the library.</comment>
        </property>
    </class>
    <version>1.0</version>
    <comment>Basic4Android applications have only one thread, the main or GUI (Graphical User Interface)
thread that, not surprisingly, handles the user interface (and everything else).
Using this library you can create additional threads that operate (apparently)
in parallel alongside each other and the GUI thread. Threads can be useful to keep
the user interface alive while performing a long sequence of computations or while
waiting for something to happen.

Such threads are not allowed to manipulate GUI elements directly but this can be
achieved by the Thread.RunOnGuiThread method that runs a Sub on the main GUI thread.

This library contains a Thread object that runs the Basic4Android Sub on a separate
thread, a Lock object to facilite orderly use of resources by different threads and
can also be used to synchronise threads and an Exception object to give more
flexibility in handling exceptions than is native to Basic4Android.</comment>
</root>
